# **Andrew Onaghise**

# **Carrier Validation Engineer - Motorola Mobility Inc**

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Andrew-Onaghise/0ddbffa4b0eb2745

A self-motivated, and task-driving professional with an analytical and technical aptitude, with over five years of relevant coursework in the IT and technology organization. Seeking an opportunity within your organization to garner on site experience as well as become a major contributor to the organization. Professional references are available if needed.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Test Engineer**

Motorola Mobility Inc - Chicago, IL - July 2014 to October 2015

Responsibilities

Executing AT&T, Verizon and T-Moble Test Plans for Motorola devices

- $= {\sf Executing\ automated\ and\ manual\ tests\ cases\ on\ Anite,\ Anritsu,\ Rhode\ \&Schwarz\ and\ Spirent\ equipment}$
- = Test RF parameters against ATT, TMO, VZW and NCC requirements
- = Using tools like QCOM, QXDM, QPST and QMICM to troubleshoot and root cause analysis ,
- = Find and reporting bugs or defects on Jira after analyzing test results.

Reliability Engineer, Motorola Mobility Inc. (Chicago, IL)

- = Design Verification testing (DvT)
- = Accelerated Life Testing (ALT)
- = Mechanical Durability Testing (MDU)
- = Electrical Durability Testing (EDU)
- = Regulatory and compliance testing
- = Analyze results with statistical tools like Minitab

#### Accomplishments

- 1. Acquired a working knowledge 3GPP, LTE call flow
- 2. Acquired knowledge of RF testing equipment and equipment .
- 3. Working knowledge of test methodologies
- 4. Working knowledge of reliability testing processes
- 5. Product live cycle

## **RF Drive Test Engineer**

Nexgen - Milwaukee, WI - February 2014 to February 2014

Market (Samsung/Spring Project)

Assignment include but not limited to:

- 4G LTE drive testing and data collection using XCAL-M, QXDM, JDSU
- 4G & 3G Cluster drives
- Data collection and processing using XCAL -M
- Cluster Test-drives using XCAL-M.
- UL/DL, RTT, CA and CTTP/e911 testing using XCAL-M
- Data Collection and frequency scan of UMTS, and GSM networks for handoffs and data throughput Test
- Post Migration drive testing using Microsoft Streets and Trips, Map Info.

## **RF Drive Test Engineer**

Erickson Project - Knoxville, TN - November 2013 to January 2014

TN Market (Erickson Project)

- UL/DL/Comparison Test of TMO, Verizon, and ATT
- Data collection using TEMS with 1 short call, 1 long call, PS call, and frequency scanning
- Analysis of TEMS logs in TEMS, ACTIX and MapInfo detailed analysis of layer 3 messaging, Call drops, access fails etc
- Troubleshooting and calibrating drive test equipments.
- Based on statistics, recommend solutions to improve performance
- Data post Migration testing the swap process by looking into the site statistics and monitoring the site performance after the swap in Actix, and developed drive routes in Microsoft Streets and Trips, Map Info

#### Research Assistant

Western Illinois University - January 2012 to December 2013

Research in material science and superconductivity

- Using Radio frequency oscillatory Circuit for precision Measurements
- o Experience in using current RF Hardware like Spectrum Analyzers, Oscilloscope, radio frequency generation etc.
- Research in Electro optic, RF Modulation Theories (CDMA, EDO, GSM/GPRS/EDGE, UMTS and LTE| VoLTE)
- Interference Testing/Patterns, Electromagnetic Studies

## Installation/Maintenance Engineer

Paqware Solutions Limited - January 2011 to December 2012

Responsibilities included Installation, configuration, Trouble shooting and maintain

- o Supported RFID (Radio Frequency Identification) systems,
- o Installed and maintained Bio-Metrics
- o Maintained Finger Print in Locks, Time clocks and Hand-Held Reader

## **IT Support Personnel**

BLW Inc - January 2008 to April 2010

Responsibilities included Systems and Network Support for a network with over 1500 users

- o Configured Cisco Routers and Switches to set policies on the user network
- o Created and managed user accounts with Active directories
- o Support servers that serves other affiliates of the organization around the world
- o Configured and Maintain Wireless access points for wireless networks in the organization

## o Configured and Supported WAN Radios

#### **EDUCATION**

# **MS** in Physics

Western Illinois University

## BS

Engineering Physics Obafemi Awolowo University

## CERTIFICATIONS

## **CCNA**

June 2008 to June 2012

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## SKILLS/PROFFICENCIES

- Knowledge of RF Design and Optimization
- Strong knowledge of GSM/GPRS/EDGE, UMTS, EVDO, LTE,
- Strong knowledge of both live and simulated RF testing
- 3G & 4G LTE network architecture
- RF testing/drive testing and trouble shooting, Signal testing E911, testing
- · Strong knowledge of routing and switching
- Experience with using Oscilloscopes, Anrithsu Spectrum Analyzer, Frequency generators,
- Experience with RF Lab simulation equipments: Anite, R&S, CMW, Anrithsu, Spirent, equipments
- Knowledge of Electromagnetic Theory, RF Theoretical Studies, Wavelength Concepts,
- Strong knowledge of VBA, C++, Python, Lab view, Mathematica, Fortran, POWER SHELL scripting, XML,
- Experienced with the use of Erickson's TEMS LTE investigation 15.\* software, Microsoft Streets and Trips, MapInfo,
- Strong knowledge of TCP/IP protocol (IPV4, IPV6)
- Microsoft Office Package (Expert Level)
- Trained Project management professional